Vince Trombetta

Wilmington, DE 19801 302-518-0692 (mobile) vjtrombetta@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/vitrombetta/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Financial Services Leader with a track record of achieving operational excellence via collaborative partnerships, data-directed insights, strategic innovation, disciplined project management, and dynamic thought leadership. Experienced in leading complex, inter-connected operational and technological initiatives across multiple lines of business, channels, customer segments, and geographies. Proven success in developing and implementing solutions that deliver key performance objectives, including world-class customer experience, efficiency, risk mitigation, and team member effectiveness.

SKILLS & EXPERIENCE

- Consumer Lending
- Small Business Banking
- Mortgage & Home Equity
- Consumer Credit Marketing
- Program Marketing
- Database Marketing
- Financial Planning & Analysis
- Advanced Analytics
- Product Development
 Marketing Operations
 - Vendor Management
 - Risk Management

- Project Management
- Operations Management
- Process re-engineering
- Direct Sales & Customer Service
 - Talent Management

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Long & Foster Real Estate, Wilmington, DE

2019-present

Direct Sales, Marketing and Operations

Responsible for Direct Sales and Marketing of Residential Real Estate as a Licensed Realtor® with Long & Foster broker affiliation. Develop sales and lead generation through community networking, purchased lead conversion, digital channels, SEO, and social media. Achieved Gold Team status based on annual Sales Volume of \$6.3 million. Proficient at using Google Business Profile Manager and Meta Business Suite.

Wells Fargo & Company, Wilmington, DE

2015-2019

Operations Initiatives Manager, SVP

2016-2019

Led planning, operations & governance for enterprise market research, marketing analytics, data platforms and infrastructure. Managed project management, process design, technological capabilities, talent management, and regulatory risk programs. Responsible for controls testing and vendor/offshore contract management.

Consumer Credit Manager Analytics, SVP

2015-2016

Responsible for the development and leadership of integrated data management, business intelligence, performance reporting, and predictive modeling services for Consumer Credit Solutions. Managed cross business, enterprise-wide collaboration initiatives.

Vince Trombetta

AlphaSights, New York, NY / Ashton212, Oakland, CA

2014-2015

Management Consultant

Delivered expert-level consulting services to banking, private equity, fintech, and global management consulting firms. Areas of expertise included commercial/small business lending operations, portfolio valuation, product development, strategic business transformation, sales/marketing efficacy, competitive research and customer insights.

Citibank, NACB, New York, New York

2010-2013

Director of Small Business Lending

Led product development (working capital, SBA and asset-based lending), acquisition and customer marketing programs, portfolio management, credit delivery process-engineering, risk-based and relationship pricing, operational and regulatory risk management, and implementation of large-scale technological initiatives to deliver credit products and services across multiple channels. Partnered extensively with global operations, retail sales, and risk to increase loan originations and prudently grow the loan portfolio.

Wells Fargo & Company, San Francisco, CA

2001-2009

Senior Customer Service Leader, SVP

2007-2009

Directed Small Business & Commercial Banking call center operations including customer service, inside sales, product fulfillment, specialized account opening, enterprise centralized banker support, and the escalation resolution team. Partnered with marketing and product development to achieve service and sales initiatives. Developed comprehensive strategies to deliver exceptional customer experiences.

Marketing Analytics Manager

2003-2007

Led strategic database marketing and decision sciences supporting Small Business Lending to deliver over 60 million contact leads per annum. Applied advanced analytics and statistical techniques to optimize programs across digital, direct mail, store and phone channels. Led the development of predictive modeling to ensure meeting success measure goals.

Division Finance Officer

2001-2003

Managed all aspects of Small Business Segment division-level strategic planning and financial management including, forecasting, pricing, financial reporting, profitability planning & analysis, portfolio valuation, acquisition due diligence, capital budgeting, and expense management.

EDUCATION

University of Baltimore, Maryland

Master of Science, Finance

Loyola College, Maryland Bachelor of Arts, Business Administration

APPLICATIONS

- Microsoft Office Suite
- Meta Business Suite
- Google Business Profile Manager
- Advanced Excel
- Salesforce Cloud Services